Angshuman Mazumdar

I believe in a simple concept: if it's a piece of engineering, it is also a work of art. Also, an ardent follower of interactive media, especially video games, because they provide a great platform for experiences to flourish, unlike any other media.



🗸 angshuman.mazumdar@gmail.com



West Lafayette, Indiana



https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/

(585)-406-9165

https://www.linkedin.com/in/angshuman-mazumdar-a0b75a130/

(O) https://binaryvectorjr.github.io/portfolio

EDUCATION

Capstone Project

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester (New York) January 2019 - May 2019

Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication)

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore 2015 - 2019 (CGPA - 8.69)

High School and Senior School

Don Bosco Senior Secondary School, Guwahati 2003 - 2015 (93.4%)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trainee

Bharati Airtel 05/2018 - 06/2018 Chandigarh, India Achievements/Tasks

- Automated data collection and organization process for SACFA Applicants (using Visual Basic for Applications) which reduced the time for data organization significantly.
- Worked on collecting the azimuth data for various sites for towers using their latitude and longitude.
- Worked on "Project Junoon" by daily updating new sites on the maps, filtering out the sites with maximum problems, and categorizing the different sites.

Graphic Designer

MOX - Movement of Expression 02/2018 - 08/2019 Shillong, India

An organization that caters to services such as Event Management, Talent Management, PR, Photography, as well as hosting various events around India Achievements/Tasks

• Designed the logos for the event "Street Sangam".

ACHIEVEMENTS

Design Head (BEAM-VIT) (06/2016 – 05/2017)

Led the design department and oversaw various design requirements of the club (BEAM VIT).

Design Co-Chair (BIDSF'17) (01/2017 – 04/2017)

BIDSF is an annual event organized by the Biotech Division of VIT with the help of various clubs. I was responsible for creating the theme, logo, posters and oversee various other design related issues for the event.

Design Advisor for Team Vimaanas (01/2017 – 06/2018)

Team Vimaanas is the official Micro-Class RC Aviation team of VIT. I was asked to help them out with their design team by organizing their workflow, as well as teaching the members about graphic design. I also helped design their brochures.

SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Premiere Pro Unreal Engine 4 Unity3D World Machine Autodesk 3DS Max Blender SketchUp Autodesk Maya C++HTML and CSS (W3 CSS) Microsoft Office Suite (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Parkinson's Disease Assist Device using Machine Learning and Internet of Things (07/2017 – 04/2018)

- The main purpose of the project was to construct a prototype of a spoon which senses the hand motion of an individual suffering from Parkinson's disease.
- It gives a counter motion to the trembling actions of a patient's hand, in order that they don't spill their food.
- Machine Learning is used to detect any anomalies in the sensor data from the device. If an anomaly is detected the device send a mail alert to the wellwishers of the patient.

Autonomous Robotic Manipulator (01/2019 - 04/2019)

- The goal was to develop the driver that will control a robotic arm
- Oversaw the robotic arm manipulation of the larger project
- Final objective was to mount the arm to the top of an autonomous base, that could enable users to control it using Virtual Reality Techniques
- Application in the Elder Care Industry
- Core skills learned: setting up drivers for a controller (here specifically it was the OpencM9.04 Control board), interfaced hardware motors with a software controller, basics of real-time interaction using virtual reality techniques.

LANGUAGES

Assamese	Native Language
English	Full Working Proficiency
Hindi	Bilingual Proficiency
French	Novice